Guide to the Thomas W. Streeter Collection of Texas Manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Personal Files, 1787-1882, WA MSS S-498
  - Fisher, William, S.
    - ALS to Gen. Pedro de Ampudia, Mier, 1842 Dec 26 (Box 2, Folder 100)
      Surrendering to General Ampudia.
  - Flores, Gaspar
    - LS to C. Receptor de la Villa Austin, Bexar, 1835 Apr 15 (Box 2, Folder 101)
      1 p. 30 cm.
      Accompanied by photostat.
      Concerns administration of taxes.
  - Ford, Christopher
    - Propositions submitted by Mr. Bland to Mr. Ford, n.p. (Box 2, Folder 102)
      2 p. 34 cm.
    - Signed note transferring land to Mary E. Huston, Natchez, 1845 Jul 10 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Gaines, Edmund Pendleton, 1777-1849
    - LS to Gen. Samuel Houston, Camp Sabine, 1836 Aug 3 (Box 2, Folder 104)
      5 p. 25 cm.
      Offers any possible help and urges
      Houston to make a treaty with
      Mexico and return the prisoner
      Santa Anna.
  - Glasscock, Hanum
    - Promissory note to Philip Nolan, Natchez, 1800 Jun 14 (Box 2, Folder 105)
      1 p. 19 cm.
      Signed with a mark, and by Andrew
      Beall, Secy.
  - Green, Thomas Jefferson, 1801-1863
    - ALS to Col. C.P. Green, Houston, Texas, 1830 Jan 9 (Box 2, Folder 106)
      Introducing Mr. Austin Bryan.
    - ALS to Gen. M.T. Hawkins, Houston, Texas, 1830 Jan 9 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - ALS to "Dear Mother," Castle of Perote, Mex, 1843 Apr 25 (Box 2, Folder 108)
      2 p. 39.5 cm.
      A letter written while a prisoner
      enclosing a copy of a letter to
      be sent to the President of the
      United States.
  - Gregory, E.W.
    - ALS to James F. Perry, New Orleans, 1842 Feb 8 (Box 2, Folder 109)
      Discusses six drafts drawn by
      Stephen F. Austin for which he was
      never reimbursed.
  - Gritten, Edward
    - ALS to Francis F. Wells, Bexar, Texas, 1835 Sep 10 (Box 2, Folder 110)
      Discusses the intentions of the
      Mexican government toward Texas.
  - Gutiérrez de Lara, Jose Bernardo Maximiliano
    - Signed document, St. Fernando, 1813 Jun 6 (Box 2, Folder 111)
      1 p. 21 cm.
      Attached is a certificate signed
      by Alex Baillie and Francis I.
      Mennessier stating that Texas and
      the Mexican republic are pledged to
      pay $38.66 to Andrew Miller.
      States that Alex Baillie, Francis
      I. Mennessier, and Henry Perry are
      the persons elected to represent
      the claims of American soldiers
      against the Mexican Republic.
  - Hadden, John
    - Deed to Benjamin Beson, San Felipe de Austin, 1825 Jan 25 (Box 2, Folder 112)
      Attested by: Stephen F. Austin,
      John Austin, William Pettus,
      Samuel Williams, and John Brown.
  - Haden, Edward
    - Petition of Edward Haden for Texas land on which to settle 800 families, Mexico (Box 2, Folder 112a)
  - Hammeken, George Louis
    - ALS to M. Austin Bryan, New Orleans, 1839 Apr 8 (Box 2, Folder 113)
      Concerns the issuance of stock in
      the Brazos and Galveston railroad.
    - ALS to M. Austin Bryan, San Luis, 1840 Aug 18 (Box 2, Folder 114)
      1 p. with address, 28 cm.
      Relates to the organization of the
      San Luis Company.
  - Handy, Robert Eden
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, Nacogdoches, 1834 Dec 19 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - ALS to David Paul Brown, Brazoria, Texas, 1836 Jan 22 (Box 2, Folder 116)
      Note at bottom signed Thomas
      Jefferson Chambers endorsing the
      letter in favor of Ira R. Lewis.
      Introducing Judge Chambers.
    - ALS to Miss Mary Williams, Brazoria, Texas, 1836 Jan 22 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Henderson, James Pinckney, 1808-1858
    - Letter to President of the Republic of Texas, M.B. Lamar, Philadelphia, 1839 Nov 29 (Box 2, Folder 118)
      10 p. 26.5 cm.
      Mutilated.
      Discusses his efforts to negotiate
      a French loan.
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, San Augustine, 1845 Jun 19 (Box 2, Folder 119)
      2 p. 24.5 cm.
      Concerns a mutual legal matter.
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, San Augustine, 1846 Jan 18 (Box 2, Folder 120)
      Discusses his intended judicial
      appointments.
  - Herrera, Jose Manuel de
    - 2 ALS to Jose Bernardo Gutierrez, New Orleans and Galveston, 1816 Aug 13 (Box 2, Folder 121)
      Second date 1816 Oct 15.
      8 p. 25 cm.
      Concerns the progress of the
      Texas revolution.
      Enclosed typed transcription.
  - Hickey, William H.
    - ALS to Felix Huston, Peach Orchard, 1846 Sep 7 (Box 2, Folder 122)
      Information about steamboats.
  - Holley, Mrs. Mary Austin, 1784-1846
    - 2 ALS to M. Austin Bryan, Lexington, Ky, 1837 Jul 17 (Box 2, Folder 123)
      Second dated 1837 Aug 27.
  - Hook, James
    - Signed report to "Right Hon. Viscount Palmerston", n.p, 1840 Apr 30 (Box 2, Folder 124)
      29 p. 31.5 cm.
      Sewn in covers.
      Concerns a plan to extend British
      commerce to Texas and abolish
      slavery there.
      A list of tariffs is at the end.
      Enclosed provenance.
  - Horton, Albert G.
    - ALS to James Carr, Matagorda, 1841 Feb 27 (Box 2, Folder 125)
      Concerns his (Horton) candidacy
      for congress.
  - Houston, Samuel, 1793-1863
    - ALS to John C. Calhoun, n.p, 1824 Apr 15 (Box 2, Folder 126)
      Asks that he be reimbursed for
      the expense of his trip to
      Staunton, Virginia.
    - ALS to Gov. Lewis Cass, Hot Springs, A.T., 1833 Jul 30 (Box 2, Folder 127)
      5 p. 24.5 cm.
      Tells of his attempts to meet with
      representatives of the Mexican
      Republic and the Comanche Indians.
    - ALS to Governor Henry Smith, Washington, 1836 Mar 4 (Box 2, Folder 128)
      Signed: Samuel Houston, John
      Forbes.
      Concerned with the efforts to
      obtain Indian lands for Texas.
    - ALS to Capt. Philip Dimitt, Head Quarters, Texas, 1836 Mar 12 (Box 2, Folder 129)
      1 p. 34 cm.
      At end: note headed "Unofficial"
      tells of the fall of the Alamo.
      Orders to fall back to head
      quarters.
  - Hunt, Abijah
    - 17 documents concerning the estate of Philip Nolan, v.p., 1801-03 (Box 3, Folder 130)
      1801 Jun 5 - 1803 Mar 19.
      21 p. 8.5-33.5 cm.
      Abijah Hunt was the administrator
      of the estate.
  - Hunt, Memucan
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, Captain Duncan's, 1841 Mar 5 (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, Galveston, 1845 Jan 26 (Box 3, Folder 132)
      Mentions uncertainty of the success
      of the annexation proposal.
  - Huston, Eliza
    - ALS to Felix Huston, Hardinsburg, 1852 Jun 21 (Box 3, Folder 133)
  - Huston, Felix, 1800-1857
    - Copy of letter to Lt. Col. Turner, Headquarters Camp Johnson, 1836 Dec 3 (Box 3, Folder 134)
      "A true copy" signed Reuben Ross,
      Aid[!] de Camp.
      Orders to examine the men at
      Colorado Pass.
    - ALS to John C. Calhoun, Natchez, 1838 Feb 11 (Box 3, Folder 135)
      4 p. 24.5 cm.
      Gives his views on the war between
      Texas and Mexico.
    - ALS to Col. William Perkins, Natchez, 1838 Mar 18 (Box 3, Folder 136)
      Gives his views on the political
      situation in Texas.
  - Ingram, Ira, 1788-1837
    - 2 signed documents about the transfer of land to L.L. Veeder, Town of Austin, 1831 Mar 7 (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - DS giving power of Attorney to Chambers and Lewis, San Felipe de Austin, 1832 Mar 20 (Box 3, Folder 138)
      Given before Horatio Chriesman.
    - ALS to William T. Austin, Matagorda, 1835 Aug 30 (Box 3, Folder 139)
      3 p. 32.5 cm.
      Concerns a convention of the
      Committee of Safety.
  - Ingram, Seth
    - ALS to Stephen Fuller Austin, L. Oak St, 1825 Feb 8 (Box 3, Folder 140)
      Concerns surveying.
    - Signed document concerning a note of S.F. Austin, n.p, 1838 Jun 2 (Box 3, Folder 141)
      2 p. 19 cm.
  - Jack, William Houston, 1806-1844
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, n.p., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 142)
      Docket: May 1841.
    - Signed memorandum of agreement between William H. and P.C. Jack and James F. Perry, Brazoria, 1838 Jan 19 (Box 3, Folder 143)
      Signed: Wm. H. and P.C. Jack by
      Wm. H. Jack, James F. Perry.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Brazoria, 1841 Jun 12 (Box 3, Folder 144)
      Concerns the trial of Adams and
      Smith.
    - Signed bill to James F. Perry, n.p, 1843 Jun 6 (Box 3, Folder 145)
      2 p. 25.5 cm.
  - Jones, Oliver, d.1866
    - ALS to Capt. Wiley [sic] Martin, Santarosa, 1834 Jun 10 (Box 3, Folder 146)
      4 p. 30.5 cm.
      Discusses the efforts of John Mason
      on behalf of the Galveston Bay and
      Texas Land Company to acquire
      colonies and also current political
  - Kaufman, David Spangler, 1813-1851
    - ALS to T.W. White, Natchitoches, 1836 Apr 19 (Box 3, Folder 147)
      Requesting to subscribe to the
      "Southern Literary Messenger".
    - Photostat copy of ALS to W. McCullough, Nacogdoches, Texas, 1838 Mar 20 (Box 3, Folder 148)
      Discusses affairs in Nacogdoches.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Nacogdoches, 1840 Jun 17 (Box 3, Folder 149)
      Concerns current political issues.
  - Kerr, James, 1790-1850
    - ALS to The Council of War, Gonzales, Guadalupe Victoria, 1835 Oct 10 (Box 3, Folder 150)
      4 p. 24 cm.
      Notification of Collinsworth's and
      Milam's capture of Fort Goliad and
      discussion of future battle plans.
    - ALS to Patrick Usher, Morales de Lavaca, 1836 Jan 14 (Box 3, Folder 151)
      Discusses the acts of the General
      Council and Texas politics.
    - ALS to Samuel Houston, Texana, 1836 Jan 21 (Box 3, Folder 152)
      1 p. 32 cm.
      Asks that Houston explain his
      statement about Kerr accepting
      a bribe.
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, Morales, Jackson Co., Tex, 1840 Jul 23 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, Lavaca, 1841 Jul 29 (Box 3, Folder 154)
      2 p. 30 cm.
      Concerns a speech Kerr made about
      the Texas Navy.
  - Kinney, Henry Lawrence, 1813-1861
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Corpus Christi, 1844 Mar 25 (Box 3, Folder 155)
      Concerns a mission to Mexico by
      Messrs. Williams and Hockley.
  - Kuykendall, James Hampton, b.1816
    - ALS to M.A. Bryan, Bastrop Co, 1856 Oct 16 (Box 3, Folder 156)
      Concerns the writing of a history
      of Texas and the use of S.F.
      Austin's papers.
  - Lefterick, Thomas
    - ALS to I.R. Lewis, Trespalacios, 1840 Dec 28 (Box 3, Folder 157)
      Concerns business.
  - Leftwich, Robert, d.1825?
    - Signed petition for Texas land to settle 600 families, Mexico, 1823 Nov 3 (Box 3, Folder 158)
      4 p. 30 cm.
      MS map on p. 4 showing proposed
      grant.
      In Spanish.
      Accompanied by typed translation,
      and photostat and photograph of
      the map.
  - Lewis, Ira Randolph, 1800-1867
    - Memorandum about land dealings with Munroe Edwards, n.p, 1837 (Box 3, Folder 159)
    - Copy of 7 items concerning a duel with Major G.M. Collinsworth, Matagorda, 1838 (Box 3, Folder 160)
      16 p. 20-33.5 cm.
  - Linn, John Joseph, 1798-1885
    - ALS to James Kerr, Guadalupe, 1835 Sep 29 (Box 3, Folder 161)
      Gives an account of the insolences
      of Mexican soldiers at Goliad and
      suggests that Cos be taken as a
      prisoner.
  - Lipscomb, Abner Smith, 1789-1856
    - ALS to Moses A. Bryan, Live Oak Cottage, 1847 Sep 20 (Box 3, Folder 162)
      Concerning business with Bryan.
  - Love, A. C.
    - 2 ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Alabama, 1840 Oct 12 (Box 3, Folder 163)
      Second item dated 1843 Apr 25.
      2 p. with address, 24.5 cm.
      Concerns an overdue debt of Sam
      Houston's.
  - Lovell, Benjamin Drake.
    - 2 documents concerned with the Lovell-Purnell land grant, Saltillo, 1825 Oct 22 (Box 3, Folder 164)
      Second item dated 1828 Mar 17, n.p.
      9 p. 31 cm.
      Sewn together.
      Certified by Juan Antonio Padilla
      and signed by Matias Garcia and
      others.
      A copy of colonization grant and
      the land title.
  - McFarlan, William
    - Title bond to L.L. Veeder, San Felipe de Austin, Texas, 1831 Jun 7 (Box 3, Folder 165)
      Signed: William McFarlan, F.W.
      Johnson, and two witnesses.
      document in the archives under the
      charge of the Alcalde of Austin.
      San Felipe de Austin, Dec 29, 1833-
      W. Barret Travis.
  - McKinney & Williams, firm, Brazoria, Texas
    - Letter of Credit to P.W. Grayson, Col. Austin, and Spencer H. Jack, Brazoria, Tex, 1834 Jul 29 (Box 3, Folder 166)
      Note at bottom signed S.F. Austin.
      McKinstry, George B., 1805-1837
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Donnybrook, 1835 Jan 5 (Box 3, Folder 167)
  - McKinstry, William C.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Matagorda, 1840 Aug 2 (Box 3, Folder 168)
      Concerning business with Lewis.
  - McLeod, Hugh, 1814-1862
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Austin, 1841 Mar 27 (Box 3, Folder 169)
      Introducing Col. P.H. Bell.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Galveston, 1846 Feb 1 (Box 3, Folder 170)
      Thanks Lewis on behalf of Genl.
      Lamar for getting possession of
      Houston's judgement against him.
  - McQueen, Thomas
    - ALS to Mrs. Ira R. Lewis, San Felipe, 1832 Aug 9 (Box 3, Folder 171)
      3 p. 31.5 cm.
      Apologizes for the circumstances of
      Col. Lewis' duel with W.H. Jack.
  - Madero, Jose Francisco
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Monclova, 1833 Apr 3 (Box 3, Folder 172)
      Discusses various laws under
      consideration by the Congress.
    - Copy of letter sent to the Ayunta- miento of San Felipe, Bejar, 1833 Jun 16 (Box 3, Folder 173)
      At top: Translation.
      Translated by Jose M.J. Carbajal,
      Bejar, June 17, 1833.
      Recommends that Texas be elevated
      to Statehood.
  - Marshpiper, S.
    - ALS to Mrs. M.C. Linn, n.p., [1835] Oct 10 (Box 3, Folder 174)
      1 p. with address, 21 cm.
      Tells of the surrender of this
      place [Goliad].
  - Mason, John Thomson, 1787-1850
    - ALS to John P. Sheldon, Mexico, 1832 Feb 20 (Box 3, Folder 175)
      3 p. with address, 25 cm.
      Concerns a proposed trip to Texas
      and gives political news of Mexico.
  - Matagorda, Texas. Citizens
    - Petition to the Congress of the State of Coahuila and Texas, Matagorda, 1834 Dec 1 (Box 3, Folder 176)
      2 p. 31.5-53 cm.
      Signed: Thomas M. Duke, Pres. and
      59 others.
      Concerns dividing the municipality
      of Matagorda.
  - McKinstry, George B.
    - [Memorial to Congress], n.p., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 176a)
      Signed: Geo. B. McKinstry and
      seven others.
      Accompanied by copy: "Drawn up
      and presented by Anson Jones",
      June 1837.
      Concerned with the establishment
      of a Board of Medical Censors.
  - Mexia, Jose Antonio, d.1839
    - ALS to John Austin, Brazoria, 1832 Jul 23 (Box 3, Folder 177)
      With typed translation.
      Concerns customs administration.
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Calvit Ranch, 1832 Jul 25 (Box 3, Folder 178)
      3 p. with address, 31 cm.
      Discusses the latest news and
      tells Austin to gather troops
      quietly.
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Mexico, 1833 Jan 17 (Box 3, Folder 179)
      4 p. 26 cm.
      Discusses current political news.
  - Mexico. Ejercito de Operaciones sobre Tejas
    - AL to the Ministro de Guerra y Marina, Bexar, 1836 Mar 3 (Box 3, Folder 180)
      Tells of the triumph at San
      Patricio.
    - ALS to El Senor Presidente Antonio Lopez de Santa Anna, San Patricio, Texas, 1836 Mar 3 (Box 3, Folder 181)
      At top of page: Ejercito de
      Operaciones Division Sobre Goliad.
      Gives an account of an engagement
      at Agua Dulce in which forty-two
      of the enemy including Dr. James
      Grant were killed.
    - AL from "Gefe del Ejercito de Operaciones de la Republica Mexicana, a los havitantes [sic] de Tejas", Bexar, 1836 Mar 7 (Box 3, Folder 182)
      Urging citizens of Texas to accept
      Mexican protection and benefits.
  - Mexico. Laws, statutes, etc.
    - Translation of the decree declaring Coahuila and Texas and New Leon states of the Federation. n.p., [1824 May 7] (Box 3, Folder 183)
      1 p. 22.5 cm.
  - Mexico. Secretaria de la Defensa Nacional
    - ALS to Vincente Filisola, Mexico, 1836 Dec 2 (Box 3, Folder 184)
      Signed: Tornel.
      Concerns the movement of troops.
    - Copy of extracts of correspondence to Martin Perfecto de Cos, n.p, 1835 Oct 30-1 (Box 3, Folder 185)
      7 p. 33.5 cm.
      At end: A copy of the original
      Feb 20, 1836 [signed] John Carson.
      Concerns the Military Administra-
      tion of the Eastern Internal
      States.
  - Mexico. Secretaria de relaciones exteriores
    - Translation of a letter to "The President of the Meeting held at the municipality of Gonzales," Mexico, 1835 Aug 12 (Box 3, Folder 186)
      2 p. 1 cm.
      "A true translation, Bexar 10th
      Sept. 1835" - Edward Gritten.
      Expressing pleasure in the
      conduct of his community.
  - Mier y Teran, Manuel de, 1789-1832
    - ALS to Stephen Austin, Matamoros, 1832 Apr 14 (Box 3, Folder 187)
      Tells of the resignation of
      Fisher.
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Hacienda del Cojo, 1832 Jun 9 (Box 3, Folder 188)
      Refers to the Law of April 6,
      [1830].
  - Miller, James B. d.1854
    - Petitions and affidavits to become trustee of the estate of John A. Schultze, San Felipe de Austin, 1833 Jun 11 (Box 4, Folder 189)
      With official attestation.
  - Montero, Manuel
    - Report of inquiry into the escape of the Mier prisoners, Matamoros, 1843 Feb 23 (Box 4, Folder 190)
      35 p. 32 cm.
      Signed: Manuel Montero and Ignacio
      Huerta.
      p. 1 and 2: Order to conduct the
      investigation. [signed] Pedro de
      Ampudia, Matamoros, Feb 21, 1843.
      p. 4: Appoints Ignacio Huerta
      secretary. [signed] P. Ampudia,
      Matamoros, Feb 21, 1843.
  - Morehouse, Edwin, 1801-1849
    - ALS to Capt. Samuel A. White, Head Quarters, Victoria, 1836 May 28 (Box 4, Folder 191)
      1 p. with address, 25 cm.
      A certificate of service.
  - Muldoon, Michael
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Saltillo, 1832 Nov 10 (Box 4, Folder 192)
    - Signed poem to Stephen Austin, n.p., n.d. (Box 4, Folder 193)
      Note to Mr. Poinsette [sic] on
      bottom dated [1837] Apr 29, New
      Orleans.
  - Musquiz, Ramon
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Bexar, 1830 Apr 29 (Box 4, Folder 194)
      Discusses the law of April 6,
      1830.
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Bexar, 1832 Aug 30 (Box 4, Folder 195)
      3 p. 21 cm.
      Tells of the revolt of the
      garrison at Bexar in favor of the
      Plan of Santa Anna.
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Bexar, 1832 Sep 13 (Box 4, Folder 196)
      Relates political news.
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Bexar, 1832 Nov 8 (Box 4, Folder 197)
      3 p. 19 cm.
      Discusses current political affairs.
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Guadalupe Victoria, 1833 Jan 20 (Box 4, Folder 198)
      Discusses political news.
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, n.p, 1833 Feb 20 (Box 4, Folder 199)
      Tells Austin that he (Austin) has
      been declared an elector for the
      district of Bexar.
  - Nolan, Philip, ca.1771-1801
    - Bill of Sale to Joseph Ballinger, Natchez., 1791 Aug 7 (Box 4, Folder 200)
      Signed: Philip Nolan, Joseph
      Ballinger, John Girault, Manuel
      Gayoso de Lemos.
      Accompanied by written
      translations.
  - Norton, Anthony Banning
    - ALS to Hon. Hugh McCulloch, Washington, 1865 Jun 26 (Box 4, Folder 201)
      Recommending Henry C. Farquhar for
      the post of Assessor of Internal
      Revenue, 1st collection district
      of Texas.
      Includes letter to Streeter.
  - Oberthier, Fred
    - 2 ALS to Maj. L. Scruggs, Canton Smith County, Texas, 1852 Mar 12 (Box 4, Folder 202)
      Second item dated 1853 Sep 20.
      8 p. 24.5-30.5 cm.
      Description of travel to and life
  - Oliver, William F.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Bastrop, 1840 Sep 7 (Box 4, Folder 203)
      3 p. 24 cm.
      Discusses Indian affairs and
      political news.
  - Padilla, Juan Antonio, d.1839
    - ALS to Stephen F. Austin, Nacogdoches, 1832 Jan 31 (Box 4, Folder 204)
      4 p. 25.5 cm.
      Concerns a land claim of
      Padilla's.
  - Parker, George D.
    - Signed document transferring power of attorney to his brother, Eugene S. Parker, Houston, 1838 [tear] 15 (Box 4, Folder 205)
    - 2 ALS to Mrs. Eunice Parker, Houston City, 1838 May 19 (Box 4, Folder 206)
      Second item dated 1838 Nov 1.
      7 p. 29-32.5 cm.
      Describing pioneer life in Texas.
    - ALS to Eugene S. Parker, Cypress Creek, Harrisburgh Co., Texas, 1840 Mar 15 (Box 4, Folder 207)
    - ALS to Rosilla E. Parker, Washington County, Texas, 1841 Aug 9 (Box 4, Folder 208)
  - Parker, Henry
    - LS to James Kerr, n.p, 1836 Jan 20 (Box 4, Folder 209)
      Signed: Henry Parker, Andrew
      Scott.
      Relates to Samuel Houston's
      statement about Kerr and others
      accepting a bribe.
  - Parra, Francisco de la
    - Signed memorandum, n.p, 1829 May 12 (Box 4, Folder 210)
      Accompanied by: list of persons
      granted land. 42 cm.
      Typed translation.
      Concerns provisions of Mexican
      Colonization Laws.
  - Patrick, James B.
    - Document signed appointing John McCoy administrator of the estate of John Jones, [Gonzales, Texas.], 1833 Jan 14? (Box 4, Folder 211)
      Signed: Green DeWitt, J.B. Patrick,
      William Leech.
  - Perry, Emily Austin Bryan
    - ALS to Moses Austin Bryan, Lexington, 1838 Aug 27 (Box 4, Folder 212)
      Concerns family matters.
  - Pinckard, Ferdinand
    - ALS to M.A. Bryan, Rodney, Miss, 1840 Aug 26 (Box 4, Folder 213)
      2 p. with address, 26.5 cm.
    - ALS to Col. I.R. Lewis, Galveston, Texas, 1842 Apr (Box 4, Folder 214)
      Concerns business affairs and his
      newspaper the "San Luis Advocate"
      becoming the "Texas Times."
  - Poinsett, Joel Roberts, 1779-1851
    - Signed document concerning Stephen Staples, Mexico, 1828 May 8 (Box 4, Folder 215)
      At top: Legacion de los Estados
      Unidos de America Mexico 8 May
      1828.
      States that Stephen Staples was a
      graduate of Bowdoin College and has
      been recommended to the Minister
      by distinguished persons.
  - Potter, Reuben Marmaduke, 1802-1890
    - ALS to M.A. Bryan, Watch Hill - Westerly, R.I., Plimpton House, 1882 Jul 16 (Box 4, Folder 216)
      Relates to his publications about
      Texas in the Magazine of American
      History.
  - Reid, Mayne, 1818-1883
    - ALS to Allyre Bureau, London, 1854 Feb 20 (Box 4, Folder 217)
      6 p. 18 cm.
      Permission to translate in French
      and publish "The Scalp Hunters"
      on p. 6.
  - Robinson, James W., 1800-1857
    - ALS to "The Honorable, the President and Members of the Convention", Wash- ington Executive department of Texas, 1836 Mar 4 (Box 4, Folder 218)
      Discusses his duty as citizen and
      Lieutenant Governor.
    - ALS to Ira R. Lewis, Victoria, 1844 Apr 6 (Box 4, Folder 219)
      Concerns business affairs.
  - Robinson, John Hamilton
    - Signed commission appointing William Arnold a Colonel in the Mexican Republican Army, n.p, 1819 May 1 (Box 4, Folder 220)
      1 p. 66.5 cm.
    - LS to Colonel William Arnold, n.p, 1819 May 8 (Box 4, Folder 221)
      1 p. 34.5 cm.
      Instructions to take possession
      of the Territory between the Rio
      Sabine and the Rio del Norte
      "unjustly claimed by His Catholic
      Majesty."
      With typescript and notes on
      Robinson.
  - Rodriguez, Nicolay
    - ALS to Senor Dn Santiago, Lipantitlan, 1839 Nov 9 (Box 4, Folder 222)
      3 p. 20 cm.
      At top of p.1: Command. Militar
      Lipantitlan.
      Note on p. 3 in different hand.
      Concerns military affairs.
  - Ross, Reuben
    - DS, Mexico, 1826 Aug 7 (Box 4, Folder 223)
      5 p. 31.5 cm.
      Concerns his petition for an
      Impresario contract.
    - DS, Saltillo, 1828 Apr 11 (Box 4, Folder 224)
      Correcting his document of Aug. 7,
      1826 about his petition for an
  - Royall, Richardson Royster, 1798-1840